Fernand Reese Tan

Front End Web Developer

818-255-8258

E-mail: tanfernand81@gmail.com **Github**: https://github.com/Ferdyboy81

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fernandtan-webdeveloper

Portfolio: https://ferdyboy81.github.io/ftan_portfolio/

I'm a web developer that utilizes creative problem solving and clean aesthetics to optimize user experience. I come from a background in information technology and visual arts, which influences my ability to quickly pick up technical concepts while also incorporating a keen sense of design.

SKILLS

• HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, JQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, Node.js, .NET, API's, Github, WordPress, Adobe Photoshop.

PROJECTS

- LegacyGames is a website I created for a gaming company. I built this website from scratch using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap and PHP.
- NADOPET is a collaborative effort to create a website database that Humane Societies could use to
 post their contact information and their adoptable pets. I helped build this project using: HTML5 |
 CSS3 | Javascript | MongoDB | Express | Angular | Nodejs | API's | Ajax | Github.
- **Flicker** is a game app that I created using HTML, CSS and Javascript. This was a very challenging project and a great learning experience since this was the first time I learned how to code in javascript.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Development 2016 - Present Web Developer

 Various Front-End Projects ranging from creating landing pages, setting up graphic designs and other miscellaneous technology as needed.

Atkinson Baker-Court Reporters 2007-Present **Litigation Support Specialist**

- Provides litigation technology support to the legal team, including database management, data manipulation and conversion.
- Communicate, correspond and interact with clients and outside entities, such as government agencies, vendors, corporations, and other law firms to gather information or data.
- Consult with Specialist and case teams to identify case, courtroom and mobile technology needs, including audio-visual equipment and presentation software options.

South Sea Surety & Insurance Inc. 2004-2005 I.T. Administrative Assistant

- Prepared and maintain computer installation upgrades and assisted CIO or MIS Manager in projects.
- Provided technical support on-site or via phone, email or help desk
- Perform security log file audits.
- Help maintain and debug website.

EDUCATION

- Web Development, Certificate 2016 General Assembly
- Health Science, Associate Degree 2014-2016 Glendale Community College
- Management Information System (M.I.S), Bachelors Degree 2001 -2005 Philippine School of Business Administration.